The Celebrity Scandal of the Victorian era.
Effie Gray is a drama film directed by Richard Laxton.
A look at the mysterious relationship between Victorian art
critic John Ruskin and his teenage bride Effie Gray.
Euphemia 'Effie' Gray, played by Dakota Fanning.
Lady Eastlake, played by Emma Thompson.
John Ruskin, played by Greg Wise.
Everett Millais, played by Tom Sturridge.
Doctor, played by Robbie Coltrane.
Margaret Cox Ruskin, played by Julie Walters.
Effie Gray is a 2014 British biographical film written by Emma Thompson and directed by Richard Laxton, starring Dakota Fanning, Emma
Thompson, Tom Sturridge, David Suchet, Julie Walters, Greg Wise, Claudia Cardinale, Robbie Coltrane, James Fox and Derek Jacobi.
It is based on the true story of John Ruskin's marriage to Euphemia
Gray and the subsequent annulment of their marriage.
Effie Gray was released worldwide by Universal Pictures in the United
Kingdom on 10 October 2014 and in America on 3 April 2015.
The film explores themes of wife, biography, love.
The tone is emotional.